

CONTACT

786-710-2309

Johnnymorrisportfolio@gmail.com

Killeen, TX

in linkedin.com/in/Jonathanmorris-333396142

EDUCATION

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA

Midwood High School, Charlotte, NC 2000 – 2004

CODING BOOTCAMP

NuCamp,

Tacoma, WA

2021

EXPERTISE

PROFESSIONAL

- Collaboration
- Adaptability
- Problem Solving
- Integrity

TECHNICAL

- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft Excel

JONATHAN MORRIS

Business Development Representative View my portfolio: Johnnymorrisportfolio.com

SUMMARY

Experienced sales leader with a demonstrated history of working in the retails sales industry. Skilled in business-to-business sales, client relationship management, coaching and developing future leaders. Strong sales professional with a passion for technology, exceeding sales goals, & bringing value to growing businesses.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Business Development Representative

2021 - Present

Colony Home Dumpster Services, Jarrell, TX

Client relationships liaison in charge of selling to and gaining new clients by uncovering the need for our dumpsters for construction projects.

- Finding leads via social media and finding construction projects with in a 60-mile radius.
- Coaching and developing peers and helping them close sales opportunities.
- Cold calling companies to uncover their projects needs to uncover opportunities for our services
- Maintaining inventory levels and acquiring new inventory regularly.
- Visiting construction sites to find out who the point of contact was for the company to gain contracts for regularly occurring projects.

Retail Sales Lead 2018 – 2021

Spectrum, Orlando, FL

Making sure location was on track to meet sales goals. Peer to peer coaching and developing of all employees in location. Assisting store manager in inventory control. Meeting with managers regularly to discuss areas of opportunity for my location.

- Providing customer service while looking for sales opportunities by use of the sales process.
- Coaching and developing peers and helping them close sales opportunities.
- Overcoming client objections by creating value around the suite of products offered by the company.
- Making sure location was never short on inventory.

Institutional Sales & Marketing Support

2017 - 2018

Broxton Capital, San Juan, Puerto Rico

Client relationships liaison in charge of selling to and gaining new clients by uncovering the need for our value investing method. Also responsible for creating and maintaining relationships with key contacts inside major investment and hedge funds.

- Cold calling and finding key contacts responsible for finding new investors to be used in the investment strategy.
- Using CRM to gauge the relationship between our advisory and the principal contact in the advisory.
- Finding out what these companies needs were when selecting new advisors for their platform

Business Sales Manager

2016 - 2017

T-Mobile Premium Retailer, Kissimmee, FL

Making sure entire region saw consistent growth in the business-to-business space. Coaching and developing all RSM's on qualifying leads and getting me involved to help close said leads. Coaching reps on using open ended questions to gain opportunities to convert normal retail customers into small business customers.

- Prioritizing leads based upon the sales cycle of the lead.
- Coached and developed RSM's to teach Reps on how to uncover qualified leads.
- Visiting retail locations to help reps close and initiate business sales and leads.
- Using CRMs to maintain and gauge client relationships to uncover opportunities
- Scheduling visits to potential client's business locations to uncover pain points
- Overcoming client objections by creating value around the suite of products offered by the company

Retail Sales Manager

2014-2016

T-Mobile, Kissimmee, FL

Making sure all employees had a well-oiled machine to work in. Responsible for over \$100k in inventory and

LANGUAGES

- ENGLISH
- SPANISH
- HTML
- CSS
- JAVASCRIPT

•

FRAMEWORKS

- BOOTSTRAP
- REACT
- REACT- NATIVE
- NODE.JS

INTERESTS

- Cooking
- Completing DIY projects
- Learning programing languages

Business Sales 2012–2014

AT&T, Kissimmee, FL

Responsible for selling all AT&T suite of products (mobile devices, home solutions, business essentials and fiber needs) to the general public. Also maintaining a close relationship with all business customers who visited the location and growing with the customer as their needs change. Responsible for growing the amount of business certified representatives in the retail location as well as the market and coaching and observing all representatives and implementing best practices market.

- Prioritizing leads based upon the sales cycle of the lead.
- Coached and developed RSM's to teach Reps on how to uncover qualified leads.
- Visiting retail locations to help reps close and initiate business sales and leads.
- Using CRMs to maintain and gauge client relationships to uncover opportunities
- Scheduling visits to potential client's business locations to uncover pain points
- Overcoming client objections by creating value around the suite of products offered by the company

Sales Representative

2011 - 2012

AT&T, Killeen, TX

Responsible for selling all AT&T suite of products (mobile devices, home solutions, business essentials and fiber needs) to the general public. Also maintaining a close relationship with all business customers who visited the location and growing with the customer as their needs change. Responsible for growing the amount of business certified representatives in the retail location as well as the market and coaching and observing all representatives and implementing best practices across the market.

- Providing customer service while looking for sales opportunities by use of the sales process.
- Coaching and developing peers and helping them close sales opportunities.
- Overcoming client objections by creating value around the suite of products offered by the company.
- Making sure location was never short on inventory.
- Offering to help with managerial tasks frequently to gain more knowledge for personal growth.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Coding Bootcamp

2021 - 2021

NuCamp, Tacoma, WA

- Dedicated over 1,000 hours of intensive hands-on training to develop dozens of web applications in React, React Native, and JavaScript
- Utilized a multitude of frameworks such as React & React-Native
- Created user-friendly sites utilizing CRUD operations and RESTful routes together with API Integration
- Collaborated to Implement front-end and back-end solutions to unique challenges and wire-frame specifications